# **JAVIER NICOLÁS BURGOS**

## **GAMF PROGRAMMER**

- nicolasb813@gmail.com
- elnicoburgos.github.io
- **\** +543874192085
- ▼ Tucumán, Argentina
- in elnicoburgos
- ElNicoBurgos

I am 24 years old. I'm a University Programmer and I'm in my last year of Computer Science at the National University of Tucumán, Argentina. In 2018 I started developing video games on my own, learning the different concepts and tools to get started in this field. Currently I'm a programmer for the Last Minute Crew team and I'm part of the Nimble Giant Entertainment

I'm passionate about game development, I love making games, I'm always looking for constant growth and learning new things about game development.

## **SKILLS**

## PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

C

C++

C# Python

SQL

### VIDEOGAME SOFTWARE

Unreal Engine 4 & 5

Unity

Construct

#### **UNREAL ENGINE 4 & 5**

AI - AI Senses

AI - Behavior Trees

**Enviroment Query System (EQS)** 

Gameplay Ability System

Networking

Unreal Motion Graphics UI Designer (UMG)

Wwise

#### **OTHER TOOLS**

Perforce

Subversion

Git

Swarm Jenkins

Jira

**EMPLOYMENT** 

#### Nimble Giant Entertainment

Game Programmer

Part of Embracer Group & Saber Interactive.

Al Programmer - Unannounced AAA FPS

Apr. 2021 to Current

Nov. 2020 to Current

Buenos Aires, Argentina

Design architecture and implement base system of enemies.

Worked on the enemies with behavior trees and the environment query system inside Unreal Engine 5.

Use the gameplay ability system of Unreal Engine 5 to give different abilities to enemies.

Implement various systems for the AI to respond to different stimuli that the players or the environment may produce. Planning with producers, product owners and game designers, implementing and maintaining new Al features into the Unreal engine 5

Gameplay Programmer - Quantum League

Nov. 2020 to Apr. 2021

Implement some abilities (GAS) of characters to work in multiplayer or single-player games.

Implementation of different UI interfaces using the UMG.

Participation in efforts to improve the quality of the code by reviewing the code.

Involved in efforts to improve the polish of the game through the resolution of various bugs.

Last Minute Crew

Generalist Programmer - Öga Project

Tucuman, Argentina lan. 2020 to Current

Involved with the design and implementation of the main mechanics

Work with the implementation of the different UI interfaces of this virtual reality game.

Implementation of different events through animations or Wwise (audio software) within Unreal Engine 4.

Worked closely with designers, artists, and other programmers to iterate on gameplay features and ensure a great player experience.

Worked in a team that used the Scrum methodology.

## **AWARDS**

ADVA (Argentine videogame developers association) · My first published videogame

Training program that provides tools for local developers to successfully create, publish and market their first game. In this program, the Project Oga was chosen among 8 projects and won the first place.

TRAIN JAM Organization · Train Jam diversity Scholarship

Feb. 2020

Sept. 2020

The applicant received a scholarship, diversity, by the Train Jam to attend the same and in turn the Game developer conference.

GIC Organization · Game Industry Conference Scholarship

Oct. 2019

The applicant received a scholarship from the event organizer to attend the Game Industry Conference.

## VOLUNTEERING

Devcom · Volunteer

Current

Cologne - Germany

Global Game Iam · Organizer

Tucuman - Argentina

Tucuman Hace Videojuegos! · Organizer

Tucuman - Argentina

It is the main event held in the city that promotes the development of video games.

EVA CORDOBA 2019 · Volunteer

Cordoba - Argentina

**Exposition Argentinian videogames** 

Community Developer Videogames Tucuman Volunteer

Tucuman - Argentina

The applicant is part of the community committee which is responsible for carrying out activities that promote and make visible the development of video games in the province.

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

2017 to Current

Associate Degree in Software Development

2017 to Mar. 2021